Keir Staple

Portland, OR

Summary

Front End Engineer with a passion for learning and a focus on growth. Graduated Epicodus where I took 4 courses (Intro, CSS, Javascript, Design) and built 13 independent projects and 4 team projects using front-end scripting and development frameworks. Interned at MIMICS where I focused on solving several design and code challenges in the Angular 2 framework. At the Port of Portland, I lead 2 projects and worked collaboratively with over 50 stakeholders to conduct usability research and build wireframes. Continuing my education through two courses at Hack University. Sharpening my skills through some awesome freelance projects. Have a B.S. and Certificate in Web and Mobile Development.

Skills

JavaScript (ES6) Git & Github

CSS3 & SASS Pair-Programming

HTML5 Responsive

Design / Cross-

React, EmberJS, Browser

Bootstrap &

jQuery Sketch & InVision

Education

Hack University

October 2016 - Present, Portland, OR
Courses focused on ReactJS and Data
Visualization to prime students to work on Hack
Oregon teams. Will create reusable React
components for use across Hack Oregon platform.

Epicodus Programming School

January 2016 - July 2016, Portland, OR Certificate in Web and Mobile Development Full-time bootcamp where I focused on front-end development and design

University of Oregon, Clark Honors College September 2010 - June 2014, Eugene, OR B.S. Environmental Science Phone: (503) 781-5630

Email: keir.staple@gmail.com
Website: http://keirstaple.com/

Github: https://github.com/keirstaple

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/keirstaple

Experience

Badgers — Freelance Web Developer

December 2016 - Present, Portland, OR

- Build web application to help manage Badgers community — a group that uses a badge-earning system to encourage members to do fun, unique activities.
- Use React and third-party dependencies (i.e. React Router v4) to build dynamic application
- Persist data using Firebase NoSQL database and the Firebase API
- Conduct research with Badgers users through UX survey
- Collaborate with UX/UI designer and another developer

MIMICS — Programming Intern

June 2016 - July 2016, Portland, OR

- Prototyped software solutions with Angular 2 Beta framework
- Created a dynamic form model in Angular 2 to easily generate new forms with validation rules
- Drew wireframes for web app dashboard using Sketch
- Created SVG animations using company's existing logo
- Created bar graph using D3.js that was responsive to new data

Port of Portland — Contractor

March 2015 - September 2016, Portland, OR

- Conducted usability research for an internal web application through focus groups and individual interviews
- Created wireframes for application development and received iterative feedback from groups
- · Documented specs for developers
- Prototyped features in Excel to track high-level environmental data and documentation related to all Port facilities and to communicate all upcoming environmental projects, work and other expenses to inform budget process